Warren King Papers
Warren King Papers
1960-1966
King, Warren.
13.5 linear ft.
Over 900 original editorial cartoons, photocopies of cartoons, sketches and a sample book.
2651128
Biographical History
Warren King (1916-1978) was an American editorial cartoonist and painter.
Born January 3, 1916, Warren King grew up on Long Island, New York. After graduating from Fordham University in 1938 with a B.S., King studied at the Grand Central School of Art and at the Phoenix Art Institute until 1941. Although trained in painting, King pursued freelance illustration work for books, movies and advertising. King worked as cartoonist Rube Goldberg’s assistant before becoming editorial cartoonist for the New York Daily News in 1955.
The National Cartoonists Society recognized King in 1968 with the best editorial cartoon award and he also received several Freedoms Foundation awards (1953, 1959-1960, 1962-1963) and a 1963 award from the National Conference of Christians and Jews. King was a member of NCS, the Society of Illustrators, and the American Association of Editorial Cartoonists. He was also active in New York journalism organizations including the Newspaper Guild of New York and the Silurians, both of which presented him with awards. King's paintings appeared at the Pentagon and the Air Force Academy in Colorado.
Due to illness, King retired from the Daily News in June 1977 and he died on February 9, 1978 in Wilton, Connecticut.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Warren King Papers consist of two series: Cartoons and Sketches. Cartoons is primarily comprised of over 900 original editorial cartoons drawn for the New York Daily News from 1960 to 1966. Several cartoons are completely undated. Many of the cartoons have notes taped on them listing the edition, final size and other instructions before the cartoon was published.
Also included in the series are 55 copies of cartoons. Notes appear providing information about the government official or personality to whom the original was sent. Also in this series is a bound sample book containing a brief biography of King, a note to the Silurians and examples of his work from the New York Daily News from 1966.
King was also the cartoonist during the 1962-1963 New York City newspaper strike. While King used cartoons to comment on many national and internation events, the cartoons present a unique look at issues and politicians particular to New York City. Included as frequent subjects were Mayors John Lindsay and Robert Wagner as well as rising crime rates, a proposed civilian police review board, off track betting and the city and state's financial problems. Also worth noting is the language used by King in his cartoons. King often labeled figures (both of actual people and his more generic characters) as "finks", "pinkos" (labor union leader Walter Reuther) and "Vietniks".
The cartoons were drawn with pen and ink and graphite on varying textures of paper. Captions appear in blue pencil and traces of pencil are visible on the artwork. Sizes vary, but the majority are approximately 18" x 24".
Sketches contains 13 preliminary pencil sketches of ideas for cartoons on paper. These measure approximately 8 1/2" x 11".
Arrangement of the Collection
The cartoons and sketches are arranged in chronological order with undated materials appearing at the end of the series.
Related Material
has collections of over one hundred cartoonists. Please refer to for a complete listing.
Subject and Genre Headings
Art -- Cartoonists; New York State; Castro, Fidel, 1926- -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Gaulle, Charles de, 1890-1970 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Johnson, Lyndon B. (Lyndon Baines), 1908-1973 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Kennedy, John F. (John Fitzgerald), 1917-1963 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Kennedy, Robert F., 1925-1968 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; King, Warren.; Khrushchev, Nikita Sergeevich, 1894-1971 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Lindsay, John V. (John Vliet) -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Mao, Zedong, 1893-1976 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Rockefeller, Nelson A. (Nelson Aldrich), 1908-1979 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Wagner, Robert F. (Robert Ferdinand), 1910-1991 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; United Nations -- Caricatures and cartoons.; United States. Congress. -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Daily news (New York, N.Y.: 1920); American wit and humor, Pictorial.; Athletes -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Caricatures and cartoons -- United States.; Cartoonists -- United States.; Cartoonists -- New York (N.Y.); Cold War -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Crime -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Editorial cartoons -- United States.; Editorial cartoons -- New York (N.Y.); Labor unions -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Police -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Social problems -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Taxation -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Transportation -- Caricatures and cartoons.; World politics -- 1945-1989 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; New York (N.Y.) -- Politics and government. -- Caricatures and cartoons.; New York (State) -- Politics and government -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Soviet Union --Politics and government -- Caricatures and cartoons.; United States -- Politics and government -- 1961-1963 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; United States -- Politics and government -- 1963-1969 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Cartoons (humorous images); Preliminary sketches.; Editorial cartoons.; Sample books.; Cartoonists.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Warren King, 1966-1968.
Inventory
- Cartoons, Click here for a detailed inventory of dates.; See below for an index to the cartoons.
  - Sample book, circa 1966; contains 12 copies of cartoons published during 1966, has a brief bio and a note to the Silurians society inside the front cover (Oversize 1)
  - 1960 Jan - Feb (Oversize 1, Folder 1)
  - 1960 Mar - Apr (Oversize 1, Folder 2)
  - 1960 May (Oversize 1, Folder 3)
  - 1960 Jun (Oversize 1, Folder 4)
  - 1960 Jul - Aug (Oversize 1, Folder 5)
  - 1960 Sep - Oct (Oversize 1, Folder 6)
  - 1960 Nov (Oversize 2, Folder 1)
  - 1960 Dec, 1960 (Oversize 2, Folder 2)
  - 1961 Jan - Mar (Oversize 2, Folder 3)
  - 1961 Apr (Oversize 2, Folder 4)
  - 1961 May (Oversize 2, Folder 5)
  - 1961 Jun (Oversize 2, Folder 6)
  - 1961 Jul (Oversize 2, Folder 7)
  - 1961 Aug - Sep (Oversize 3, Folder 1)
  - 1961 Oct - Nov (Oversize 3, Folder 2)
  - 1961 Dec, 1961 (Oversize 3, Folder 3)
  - 1962 Jan - Feb (Oversize 3, Folder 4)
  - 1962 Mar (Oversize 3, Folder 5)
  - 1962 Apr (Oversize 3, Folder 6)
  - 1962 May (Oversize 4, Folder 1)
  - 1962 Jun (Oversize 4, Folder 2)
  - 1962 Jul - Aug (Oversize 4, Folder 3)
  - 1962 Sep (Oversize 4, Folder 4)
  - 1962 Oct (Oversize 4, Folder 5)
  - 1962 Nov (Oversize 4, Folder 6)
  - 1962 Dec, 1962 (Oversize 4, Folder 7)
  - 1963 (Oversize 4, Folder 8)
  - 1964 Jan (Oversize 5, Folder 1)
  - 1964 Feb (Oversize 5, Folder 2)
  - 1964 Mar (Oversize 5, Folder 3)
  - 1964 Apr, April 29 cartoon bears stamp from when it was used in Life magazine (Oversize 5, Folder 4)
  - 1964 May (Oversize 5, Folder 5)
  - 1964 Jun (Oversize 5, Folder 6)
  - 1964 Jul (Oversize 6, Folder 1)
  - 1964 Aug (Oversize 6, Folder 2)
  - 1964 Sep (Oversize 6, Folder 3)
  - 1964 Oct (Oversize 6, Folder 4)
  - 1964 Nov (Oversize 6, Folder 5)
  - 1964 Dec (Oversize 6, Folder 6)
  - 1965 Jan (Oversize 7, Folder 1)
  - 1965 Feb (Oversize 7, Folder 2)
  - 1965 Mar (Oversize 7, Folder 3)
  - 1965 Apr (Oversize 7, Folder 4)
  - 1965 May (Oversize 8, Folder 1)
  - 1965 Jun (Oversize 8, Folder 2)
  - 1965 Jul (Oversize 8, Folder 3)
  - 1965 Aug (Oversize 8, Folder 4)
  - 1965 Sep (Oversize 8, Folder 5)
  - 1965 Oct (Oversize 8, Folder 6)
  - 1965 Nov (Oversize 8, Folder 7)
  - 1965 Dec, includes 3 copies of cartoons (Oversize 9, Folder 1)
  - 1965, includes cartoon for which King was awarded the Freedom Foundation Medal of Honor (Oversize 9, Folder 2)
  - 1966 Jan (Oversize 9, Folder 3)
  - 1966 Feb, includes 1 copy of a cartoon (Oversize 9, Folder 4)
  - 1966 Mar (Oversize 9, Folder 5)
  - 1966 Apr, includes 1 copy of a cartoon (Oversize 9, Folder 6)
  - 1966 May, includes 2 copies of cartoons (Oversize 10, Folder 1)
  - 1966 Jun, includes 2 copies of cartoons (Oversize 10, Folder 2)
  - 1966 Jul - Aug (Oversize 10, Folder 3)
  - 1966 Sep (Oversize 10, Folder 4)
  - 1966 Oct (Oversize 10, Folder 5)
  - 1966 Nov (Oversize 10, Folder 6)
  - 1966 Dec (Oversize 11, Folder 1)
  - undated, includes 14 copies of cartoons (Oversize 11, Folder 2)
  - undated, includes 15 copies of cartoons (Oversize 11, Folder 3)
  - undated, includes 15 copies of cartoons (Oversize 11, Folder 4)
  - undated (Oversize 11, Folder 5)
  - undated, includes 2 copies of cartoons (Oversize 11, Folder 6)
- Sketches, 16 items
  - Preliminary sketches (Box 1)
    29 Nov 1966
    1 Dec 1966
    24 Dec 1966
    29 Dec 1966
    30 Dec 1966
    undated
Index to cartoons
The following is a list of predominant people, places and subjects appearing in the editorial cartoons in this collection. The list is not exhaustive. Some subjects may require you to browse with alternative terms.
B= Box, F= Folder. For example: B1F1= Box 1 Folder 1.
Ackley, Gardner B11F4
Adenauer, Konrad B1F2
AFL-CIO B2F3 B4F3 B7F2 B9F4 B10F2 B11F3 B11F6
Africa B1F6 B2F2-B2F3 B5F5 B6F5-B7F2 B8F6 B9F1
airline industry B3F5 B10F6
Albania B5F2
Algeria B2F4
aluminum industry B8F7
Americans for Democratic Action B6F2-B6F3 B7F4 B8F6 B9F4
anti-trust laws B5F1
Argentina B3F5 B10F2
armed forces B1F1 B1F3 B4F4 B6F6 B8F1 B8F3-B8F4 B9F4 B10F3-B10F4 B11F2 B11F4
Asia B5F2 B5F5 B7F1 B8F4 B9F1 B10F4
automation B11F1
Baker, Bobby B5F2-B5F4 B6F1 B6F4 B7F3 B8F1 B10F1 B11F5
banking industry B11F2
Beame, Abraham B7F1 B8F2 B8F5-B8F
Ben Bella, Ahmed B4F3
Berlin B1F2 B1F6 B2F3-B2F4 B2F7-B3F2 B3F5-B4F1 B4F4-B4F5 B4F7 B6F2
Berlin Wall B4F5 B6F1 B6F4 B8F4
big business B5F1 B6F2
bigotry B1F1 B1F6 B3F2
blind B7F3
bohemians B9F5
bossism B4F4 B10F3 B11F3
boycotts B5F1 B6F5
Brazil B5F4
Brezhnev, Leonid Ilyich B6F4-B7F1 B10F2 B10F4 B10F6 B11F5-B11F6
Britain B1F1 B1F6 B3F6 B4F7 B5F1-B5F2 B5F4 B6F6 B8F4 B10F5 B11F1
Buckley, Charles B4F4 B6F2
Buckley, William B8F5
Buddhists B9F6
budget B3F4-B3F5 B4F1-B4F2 B5F1
business B3F3 B3F6-B4F1 B4F5 B5F4 B9F1 B10F4 B10F6
Butler, Paul M. B1F5
California B5F6
capital punishment B2F7 B3F4
capitalism B1F4 B4F1
Carlino, Joseph B5F6
Castro, Fidel B1F2 B1F4-B1F6 B2F2 B2F4-B2F7 B3F2-B3F4 B3F6 B4F4-B4F6 B5F1-B5F2 B5F4 B5F6-B6F1 B6F4 B6F6 B7F3 B8F1 B8F7 B9F3 B10F2 B11F1 B11F5
Central Intelligence Agency B2F5 B10F1
China B1F4 B2F1 B3F1 B3F6 B4F2 B5F2 B6F5-B6F6 B7F2 B7F4 B8F4-B8F7 B9F4 B9F6 B10F4-B11F1 B11F3
Churchill, Winston B6F5
cities B10F2-B10F3
City College of New York B10F6
civil rights B1F5 B2F1 B4F8 B5F4-B5F5 B6F1 B6F1-B6F4 B6F6 B7F3 B9F6 B10F4 B11F2
Cold War B2F3
college students B9F6 B10F2-B10F3 B10F6
colonialism B4F6 B5F3
common market B3F2
communism B1F2 B1F4 B2F2 B2F5-B2F6 B3F4 B3F6-B4F1 B4F7 B5F4 B5F6-B6F1 B6F3-B6F5 B7F3-B8F1 B8F4 B8F7 B9F3 B9F6 B10F2 B10F4-B10F5
Condon-Wadlin Law B7F2 B9F4 B9F6
conflict of interests B2F3
Congo B1F5 B2F4 B3F1 B3F3 B3F6 B4F2 B6F3 B6F5 B7F2 B11F2
Congress B1F4 B2F6 B4F1-B4F5 B5F3 B5F5 B6F2 B6F6 B8F2 B9F3-B9F4 B10F1-B10F3 B10F6-B11F6
Connecticut B1F2
consumers B7F4 B10F6
cost of living B1F3 B1F6 B8F5 B9F1 B11F3
crime B2F4 B3F1 B4F3 B5F4-B6F1 B6F6-B8F2 B8F4 B8F7-B9F1 B9F3-B9F5 B11F5-B11F6
Cuba B1F5 B2F2 B2F4-B2F5 B4F2 B4F4-B4F6 B5F2-B5F3 B6F1-B6F4 B8F1 B10F2 B11F1
Cuban Missile Crisis B4F5
Curtis LeMay B5F4 B8F6
daylight savings time B6F2
de Gaulle, Charles B2F4 B3F5-B3F6 B5F1-B5F3 B6F1-B6F2 B6F5 B7F1 B7F3 B8F3 B9F1 B9F5 B10F1-B10F2 B11F1 B11F4
defense B1F1 B1F4 B2F5 B2F7 B3F2 B4F8 B6F6
Democratic Party B1F3-B1F5 B2F2 B4F4 B5F4 B6F1-B6F2 B6F5 B8F1 B8F6 B9F6-B10F1 B10F3-B10F4
demonstrations B5F5 B6F1 B6F5 B7F3 B8F7 B9F5 B11F2
DeSapio, Carmine B4F7
Dewey, Thomas B1F5 B6F3
Dirksen, Everett B8F3 B11F3-B11F4
disarmament B1F2 B1F6 B3F5 B6F4 B7F2 B7F4 B9F3
diseases B1F1 B2F3 B6F5
Dominican Republic B3F2 B7F4-B8F1 B8F5 B10F2
Douglas-Home, Alec B4F5 B5F2-B5F3
draft B11F4 B11F6
drugs B6F5 B7F1 B8F2 B9F6
economy B1F6 B2F3 B2F7 B3F3 B3F5 B5F4
education B2F2 B3F4 B5F5 B6F4 B8F7 B10F4 B11F5
Eisenhower, Dwight B1F2-B1F3 B1F5-B2F1 B2F3 B5F6-B6F1
elections B1F1 B1F5 B4F1 B5F1 B5F5-B6F1 B6F3-B6F6 B7F3 B8F2 B8F6-B8F7 B9F6 B10F5
En-lai, Chou B3F2
Erhard, Ludwig B6F1
espionage B1F3-B1F4 B2F1 B2F4 B2F7 B7F3 B10F1
Europe B3F2 B4F1 B6F3 B7F1
Faisal of Saudi Arabia B10F2
farmers B4F2 B7F4 B10F3
farming B1F5 B2F1 B4F8 B5F5 B11F5
Federal Bureau of Investigation B1F4 B7F4
Federal Trade Commission B5F6
fire departments B2F3 B3F1
foreign aid B2F1 B2F7 B4F1-B4F3 B4F8 B8F3 B9F6 B10F5-B10F6 B11F2 B11F4
Formosa B8F2
France B1F6 B5F2 B7F4 B11F4
free enterprise B7F4 B9F2
free press B1F3 B1F6
freedom of information B2F5 B10F2
Freeman, Orville B10F3
Frondizi, Arturo B3F5
Fulbright, J. William B8F2 B8F5 B9F4 B9F6
gambling B2F1-B2F2 B3F5 B4F7 B5F5 B6F5 B7F2-B7F3 B8F1 B9F1 B10F6
Gandhi, Indira B10F5
Georgia B1F6
Germany B1F1 B2F1 B2F6 B3F1 B4F1-B4F2 B4F7 B5F3 B5F5 B11F2
gold reserve B4F1
Goldberg, Arthur B11F1
Goldwater, Barry B5F5-B6F4 B7F4
government B1F6 B4F1-B4F2 B6F5
government spending B3F2 B3F5 B4F2-B4F3 B5F2 B5F5 B6F5 B8F2 B8F7-B9F1 B10F5-B10F6
Great Society B6F4 B7F1-B7F2 B8F6 B9F1 B9F5 B11F2-B11F4
Gromyko, Andrei B1F3 B4F5 B6F6
Gross, Calvin B5F6-B6F1
Guantanamo Bay B5F2 B11F5
Guatemala B2F1
Guevara, Che B11F5
Guinea B10F6
guns B8F1
Hall, Gus B5F1 B10F3 B11F2
Hammarskjold, Dag B1F6
healthcare B7F3 B8F4
Hitler, Adolph B4F7
Ho Chi Minh B7F2 B7F4 B8F3 B8F7 B9F6 B10F3 B10F5-B11F4 B11F6
Hoffa, Jimmy B2F7 B5F1 B11F1
holidays B6F6 B8F7-B9F1 B10F6
HUAAC B7F3 B8F6
Humphrey, Hubert B3F2 B3F6 B6F2-B6F3 B7F4 B9F4-B9F5 B11F6
Hungary B2F4-B2F5 B4F3 B10F5
hunger B4F2 B6F3 B9F6 B10F5-B10F6
Illia, Arturo Umberto B10F2
imperialism B3F2 B7F2 B9F5
India B4F6 B8F5
Indonesia B6F6 B9F3
inflation B1F6 B2F3 B3F3 B6F2 B8F3 B8F5 B9F5 B10F3 B10F5-B10F6
International Longshoremen's Association B1F2 B7F2
Jackson, Andrew B5F3
Japan B2F6 B3F1
Javits, Jacob B9F5 B10F4
Jews B5F1 B10F2
Johnson, Lyndon Baines B1F4-B1F5 B4F5 B5F1 B5F3-B6F5 B7F1-B8F3 B8F5-B9F1 B9F4 B10F1 B10F4 B11F2-B11F3 B11F5-B11F6
Jones, Howard P. B3F4
judicial system B6F5-B6F6 B10F2 B11F5
Kai-shek, Chiang B4F3
Keating, Kenneth B5F5 B6F4
Kefauver, Estes B3F6
Kennedy, Caroline B3F5
Kennedy, Jacqueline B3F5
Kennedy, John F. B1F4-B2F5 B2F7-B4F1 B4F3-B4F5 B4F7 B8F1
Kennedy, Robert F. B2F2 B2F4 B6F2 B6F4-B6F5 B8F6 B9F4-B9F5 B10F2-B10F6 B11F3 B11F6
Kennedy, Ted B11F6
Khanh, Nguyen B6F3
Khrushchev, Nikita B1F1-B2F1 B2F3-B3F6 B4F2-B4F4 B4F6-B6F4 B7F1 B8F3 B8F6
Kissinger, Henry B3F4
Korea B2F5 B3F6
Kosygin, Alexey B6F4-B6F5 B7F2 B9F1 B11F5
Ku Klux Klan B7F3-B7F4 B8F6 B11F5
labor B2F4 B2F7 B4F1 B5F1 B5F4 B8F7-B9F1 B9F5 B11F6
Laos B2F3-B2F6 B4F2 B4F5
Latin America B2F4 B3F4 B5F6 B6F6-B7F1 B8F1 B8F7
Lebanon B2F3
Levitt, Arthur B3F1
liberty B4F3
Lincoln, Abraham B7F2
Lindsay, John B8F2-B8F3 B8F5-B8F7 B9F3-B10F5 B11F1 B11F3-B11F4
Lodge Jr., Henry Cabot B5F5-B6F1 B8F3
López Mateos, Adolfo B5F3
lottery B2F1 B3F1 B3F4 B4F1 B10F4
Mac Mahon, Doug B9F3
MacArthur, Douglas B2F2 B11F5
MacMillan, Harold B3F2
Makarios III B6F4
Malinovsky, Rodion B2F5
Mansfield, Mike B9F6 B10F2 B11F1
Marxism B11F5
May Day B4F1
McNamara, Robert B5F4 B6F6 B10F5 B11F5
Meany, George B4F3 B10F2 B11F3 B11F6
Medicare B1F3 B4F2 B7F4 B8F3 B10F5
Meredith, James B10F2
metric system B8F1
Mexico B1F5 B3F3
Mikoyan, Anastas B3F1
mining B8F1
Monroe Doctrine B2F1 B3F5
morality B3F2
Morgenthau, Robert B4F4 B4F7
Morse, Wayne B10F4
Moses, Robert B7F1 B9F5
Murphey, Robert D. B5F3
Muslims B7F3
Nasser, Gamal Abdel B1F3 B1F6 B2F3 B4F3 B5F5 B6F4 B6F6-B7F2 B10F5
national debt B2F6 B5F5
National Youth Organization B5F1
NATO B1F1 B4F4 B5F2 B5F5 B6F5 B10F1
natural disasters B4F4 B8F3 B11F5
natural resources B9F3 B9F6 B11F5
Nazism B2F4-B2F5 B6F3
Nehru, Jawaharlal B4F2 B4F5
Netherlands B3F4 B11F2
neutrality B1F6
New Jersey B1F2 B3F5
New York (State) B2F7 B3F4 B4F1 B4F7 B6F4-B6F6 B7F3-B7F4 B8F2-B8F3 B8F6 B9F3 B9F6-B10F1 B11F5
New York City B1F1 B1F6 B2F3-B2F4 B3F1 B3F3 B3F5 B5F1 B5F4-B6F1 B6F6 B7F2-B7F3 B8F1-B8F3 B8F5-B9F1 B9F3-B10F3 B10F5-B11F1 B11F3-B11F4
New York State Legislature B5F6 B7F1-B7F2 B9F4-B9F6 B10F3
Nicaragua B2F1
Nixon, Richard M. B1F3-B1F4 B1F6 B5F6 B6F5
Nkrumah, Kwame B2F2 B8F6
nuclear weapons B2F2 B2F6-B3F2 B3F4-B3F6 B4F3-B4F6 B5F3-B5F4 B5F6 B6F4-B6F5 B7F1-B7F2 B8F7-B9F1 B10F5
O'Connor, Frank D. B9F4 B10F1 B10F3-B10F5
Organization of American States B5F2 B6F1
organized crime B2F2 B2F4
Oswald, Lee Harvey B8F1
Pakistan B3F4 B8F5
Panama B5F1-B5F3
Passman, Otto B4F3
peace B1F6 B2F3-B2F4 B3F1 B7F1 B8F3-B8F4 B9F3 B9F5 B10F4-B10F5 B11F6
Peace Corps B2F3 B10F6
Pearl Harbor B11F1
Pennsylvania B1F1
Pentagon B2F6 B4F4
Peron, Juan Domingo B6F6 B10F2
Poland B4F2 B8F5
police B2F4 B3F2-B3F3 B5F4 B6F1 B7F2-B7F3 B8F1-B8F2 B9F1 B9F3 B9F5 B10F2-B10F6 B11F4-B11F5
police brutality B3F5 B10F1
politics B1F5 B4F1-B4F2 B8F3 B10F5
population B6F3
poverty B2F3 B3F2 B6F2 B7F2 B8F3 B8F5 B9F3 B10F1-B10F2
Powell Jr., Adam Clayton B6F2 B7F4
press B9F5 B11F5
prosperity B6F2
Prouty, Winston B9F5
Quill, Michael B1F6 B3F5 B8F7
racism B5F1 B5F5 B7F3 B10F1
railroad industry B4F3 B5F4 B6F5 B7F1 B7F3 B8F2 B11F4 B11F6
Rayburn, Sam B2F3
religion B1F1-B1F2 B2F1-B2F2 B3F2 B9F1 FAITH
Republican Party B1F3-B1F4 B2F7 B3F6 B4F4 B4F6 B5F5 B6F1 B6F5 B8F1 B8F3 B8F6 B9F1 B10F2 B10F4 B10F6
Reuther, Walter B4F1 B4F3 B10F2 B11F3
Rhodesia B11F1
right to work law B8F1 B9F3 B11F4
riots B6F1 B6F6
Rockefeller, Nelson B1F1 B1F3-B1F4 B2F3 B3F5 B4F1 B4F4 B4F7 B5F1-B5F2 B5F5-B6F2 B6F4-B7F3 B8F1 B9F3-B9F4 B10F2-B10F5
Romania B5F6 B8F5
Romney, George W. B5F6
Roosevelt Jr., Franklin D. B10F1 B10F3 B10F6
Roosevelt, Franklin D. B2F1 B3F5 B4F7
Ruanda-Urundi B4F2
Rusk, Dean B3F2 B3F5 B4F5 B5F1 B6F2 B8F7
Russia B1F3 B2F2 B2F5-B2F6 B3F1-B3F2 B3F5 B4F2 B5F1 B5F4 B7F1 B8F4 B9F4
school prayer B9F1 B11F4
schools B2F7-B3F1 B3F4 B3F6 B5F1 B5F3 B5F5-B6F1 B9F1 B9F5 B10F4 B10F6
science B1F1 B2F1 B2F5
Scranton, William B5F6-B6F1 B10F2
Shelepin, Alexander B7F1 B11F6
shipping industry B1F2
smoking B5F6 B7F3
social security B9F5
socialism B7F4 B8F5
South America B1F2
South Korea B8F2
Soviet Union B1F1-B1F5 B2F1 B2F7 B3F4-B3F6 B4F2-B4F7 B5F2-B5F3 B6F4 B6F6 B7F2-B7F3 B8F1-B8F5 B9F1 B10F4 B10F6 B11F5-B11F6
space exploration B1F2 B1F5-B1F6 B2F4-B2F5 B2F7 B3F4 B4F4 B5F4 B7F3 B9F2-B9F3 B10F2 B11F1
Spain B6F6
sports B2F2
states' rights B8F3 B10F3
steel industry B3F6 B7F3 B11F4
Steingut, Stanley B6F2
Stevenson, Adlai E. B1F4-B1F5 B2F2 B3F3 B4F5 B5F3
stock market B5F3 B8F6 B10F1
strikes B3F5-B3F6 B5F4 B6F5 B7F2-B7F3 B8F3 B9F1 B9F3 B9F6 B11F6
Sukarno B6F4 B9F3
Supreme Court B3F4 B5F6 B6F2 B6F6 B7F3 B8F2-B8F3 B8F7-B9F1 B10F2 B11F2 B11F4
Symington, Stuart B1F2 B1F4
Taiwan B8F3
tariffs B3F2 B5F5
taxes B1F1-B1F2 B1F4 B2F1-B2F3 B2F5-B2F6 B3F2-B4F3 B5F1-B5F2 B5F5-B5F6 B6F4-B7F4 B8F3-B8F6 B9F1 B9F3-B11F1
telecommunications B4F3-B4F4 B5F1
television B1F5
Thant, U. B3F2 B6F2 B6F6 B7F3 B10F4 B11F6
Tito, Josip Broz B1F6 B3F3 B6F4 B10F4-B10F5
trade B3F4 B5F1-B5F3 B5F5-B5F6 B6F6 B7F4 B8F5 B11F6
transit and transportation B1F1-B1F2 B1F4-B1F6 B3F5 B5F4-B5F5 B6F5-B6F6 B7F3 B8F3 B9F1 B9F3 B9F5 B10F2-B10F3 B11F1 B11F4
Travia, Anthony J. B9F6 B10F2
trucking industry B5F1
Truman, Harry S. B1F5 B2F2
Tshombe, Moise B6F2
Tunisia B2F7
tyranny B2F3
unemployment B2F7 B3F2 B10F5
unions B8F1 B9F3
United Auto Workers B6F3
United Nations B1F6 B2F2 B2F4 B2F7-B3F4 B3F6 B4F5-B4F7 B5F4-B5F5 B6F2-B7F2 B7F4 B8F2 B8F4-B8F5 B8F7-B9F1 B10F1 B10F4-B11F1 B11F3 B11F6
United States Information Agency B7F4
urban renewal B7F3
Venezuela B5F3
Vietnam B3F6 B5F3
Vietnam War B5F6-B6F3 B6F6 B7F2-B9F1 B9F4-B10F5 B11F1-B11F2 B11F5-B11F6
violence B5F2 B5F6 B6F3 B10F3-B10F4 B11F2
voting B1F1 B1F3 B1F5-B2F1 B2F7 B5F1 B6F5 B10F3-B10F4 B10F6
Wagner, Jr. Robert F. B2F3-B2F4 B3F1-B3F2 B3F5 B4F3-B4F4 B4F7 B6F2 B6F5 B7F3-B8F2 B8F7 B10F1 B11F3
Walker, Edwin A. B3F6
war B1F3 B2F3 B5F4
War on Poverty B5F5 B7F4
Warren Commission B5F2
welfare B2F3 B2F7 B3F1 B6F5 B8F1 B8F6 B9F1 B10F4
welfare state B1F2 B1F4 B2F2 B2F6 B3F6 B6F6
Wilson, Harold B6F6 B7F4 B8F3
women B5F5 B11F1
World Federalist Movement B8F2
World's Fair B5F6 B7F1
youth B5F1 B9F3 B9F5 B11F5
Yugoslavia B10F4
Zedong, Mao B1F4 B2F3 B2F5 B4F3 B4F5 B5F1 B5F4-B5F6 B6F2-B6F5 B7F2 B8F3 B8F6-B8F7 B9F6 B10F2 B10F5-B10F6 B11F4-B11F6
Zorin, Valerian B2F2 B2F4